# Sidi Mohamed Sid'El Moctar

### PhD Student · Computer Science

I am a Machine Learning PhD student at the University of Technology of Compiègne. My research focuses on applying Machine/Deep Learning for biomedical siganl processing. I want to introduce novel, efficient and interpretable data-driven representation learning techniques with a particularl interest to sparse, hybrid as well as deep representations.

Education \_\_\_

# University of technology of Compiègne

Compiègne, France

Dec 2021 - present

PHD COMPUTER SCIENCE

- These title: Data Driven Representation Learning for Biomedical Data Classification
- Advisors: Prof. Sofiane Boudaoud and Dr. Imad Rida

University of LilleLille, FranceMS DATA SCIENCE IN HEALTHCARE2019 - 2021

- · These title: Comparison between relational database and graph-oriented database for the contact tracing
- · Advisor: Dr. Antoine Lamer

University of Lille, France

### BS MATHEMATICS, STATISTICS & BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE

2018 - 2019

- These title: Comparison of exact and asymptotic confidence intervals for a proportion
- · Advisor: Dr. Baba Thiam

## University of Nouakchott

Nouakchott, Mauritania

2015 - 2018

BS MATHEMATICS APPLIED TO ECONOMICS AND FINANCE

# Professional Experience \_

Dec 2021- PhD Candidate, Université de technologie de Compiègne: Data Driven Representation Learning for Biomedical

**present** Data Classification

Sep 2022present Graduate Teaching Assistant, Université de technologie de Compiègne : Data Analysis, Statistics

Oct 2020-Sep 2021 Data Analyst, Oscar Lambret Center

Mar 2020-Aug 2020 Data Scientist intern, Lesaffre International

Publications \_\_

## ACCEPTED

**S Moctar, SM**, Diab, A, Rida, I, Kinugawa, K, Boudaoud, S. 2023. Active aging prediction from muscle electrical activity using HD-sEMG signals and machine learning. IEEE 36th International Symposium on Computer-Based Medical Systems — CBMS 2023.

SIDI MOHAMED SID'EL MOCTAR

**S Moctar, SM**, Rida, I, Boudaoud, S. 2023. Time-domain features for sEMG signal classification: A brief survey. JETSAN symposium 2023.

## **SUBMITTED**

**S Moctar, SM**, Rida, I, Boudaoud, S. Comprehensive Review of Feature Extraction Techniques for sEMG Signal Classification: From Handcrafted Features to Deep Learning Approaches (*Submitted* - Elsevier IRBM)

## IN PREPARATION

**S Moctar, SM**, Rida, I, Kinugawa, K, Boudaoud, S. CNN-Based Classification of Active Aging Using Time-Frequency Representation of HD-sEMG Signals

S	ki	U	lS	
			_	
•	I/ I		ıc.	
. 1	nı		•	
_	٠.,	•		

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING Python, R, SQL, Neo4j, Power BI

DATA SCIENCE LIBRARIES Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Plotly, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION GNU/Linux, MacOS X, Git

LANGUAGES English, French, Arabic

# References \_\_\_\_

SOFIANE BOUDAOUD Full Professor, Université de technologie de Compiègne, sofiane.boudaoud@utc.fr

IMAD RIDA Associate Professor, Université de technologie de Compiègne, imad.rida@utc.fr

ANTOINE LAMER Associate Professor, Université de Lille, antoine.lamer@univ-lille.fr

MARIE-CÉCILE LE DELEY Head of Promotion, Methodology and Biostatistics in The Clinical Research and Innovation

Department, Centre Oscar Lambret, m-ledeley@o-lambret.fr